const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",a=200,i=120,t=[{id:177,question:"The ores that can be concentrated by flotation are",option:{a:"Nitride ores",b:"Chloride ores",c:"Oxide ores",d:"Sulphide ores"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:36,question:"When chlorine is passed into water and the resulting solution exposed to sunlight, the product formed are",option:{a:"Chlorine gas and hydrogen",b:"Oxygen and oxochlorate(l) acid",c:"Hydrochloric acid and oxygen",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:10,question:"The pollution from petroleum spillage in rivers and lakes can best be dispersed by",option:{a:"Pouring detergents",b:"Passing of ships through the area",c:"Pouring organic solvents",d:"Evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:268,question:"The maximum number of electrons in the L shell of an atom is",option:{a:"8",b:"18",c:"32",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:5,question:"An oxide X02 has a vapour density of 32. What is the atomic mass of X [O = 16]",option:{a:"32",b:"20",c:"14",d:"12"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:273,question:"Calculate the solubility in mol dm -3 of 40g of Cu So4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1200C  {Cu = 64, S = 32, 0 = 16}",option:{a:"2.5",b:"0.4",c:"0.25",d:"4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:247,question:"Water has the ability to dissolve almost all substances because its molecule has a structure with",option:{a:"One positive end and one neutral end",b:"Two positive ends",c:"One positive end and one negative end",d:"Two negative ends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:25,question:"3CU(s)  +  8HNO3(aq) →  3Cu(NO3)2(aq)  +  4H2O(I)  +  2NO(g)  In the equation above, copper is",option:{a:"An electron acceptor",b:"A base",c:"An oxidizing agent",d:"A reducing agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following organic compounds is very soluble in water",option:{a:"C2H2",b:"C2H4",c:"CH3COOC2H5",d:"CH3COOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:71,question:"Which of the following gives a precipitate when treated with NaOH solution",option:{a:"Na2CO3",b:"CH3COONa",c:"NH4Cl",d:"AlCl3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:133,question:"Chlorine consisting of two isotopes of mass numbers 35 and 37 in the ratio 3:1 has an atomic mass of 35.5. Calculate the relative abundance of the isotope of mass number 37.",option:{a:"20",b:"25",c:"60",d:"75"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:286,question:"In the preparation of oxygen by heating KCIO3 in the presence of MnC2, only moderate hear is needed because the catalyst acts by",option:{a:"Increasing the surface area of the reactant",b:"Increasing the rate of the reaction",c:"Lowering the energy barrier of the reaction",d:"Lowering the pressure of the reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:15,question:"The chemiocal used for coagulation in water purification is",option:{a:"Aluminum tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Copper tetratoxosulphate (VI)",c:"Sodium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",d:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate (VI)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:107,question:"Which of the following statements is true of sulphur (IV) oxide",option:{a:"It forms Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid with water",b:"It is an odourless gas",c:"It is an acid anhydride",d:"It forms white precipitate with acidified barium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:214,question:"2H2 + O2  → 2H2O  ΔH = -571Kj  In equation above, how much heat will be liberated if 12.0g of hydrogen is burnt in excess oxygen?",option:{a:"-1713kJ",b:"+1142kJ",c:"-571kJ",d:"-1142kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:276,question:"The acid that is used to remove rust is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric",b:"Trioxonitrate (V)",c:"Tetraoxosulphate (VI)",d:"Boric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:222,question:"In the electrolysis of CuSO4(aq) using platinum electrodes, the reaction at the anode is",option:{a:"4H+  +  4e-  → 2H2",b:"2OH  +  2OH-  →  2H2O + O2",c:"2OH-  - 2e-    → 2OH",d:"4OH-  -  4e- →  2H2O + O2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:17,question:"In which of the following reactuions does reduction take place",option:{a:"Fe2+ - e-   Fe3+",b:"2O2-  → O2 + 4e-",c:"Cr - 2e-  → Cr2+",d:"2H+  +  2e-   →H2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:47,question:"The formula CH2O for ethanoic acid is regarded as its",option:{a:"General formula",b:"Structural formula",c:"Molecular formula",d:"Empirical formula"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:211,question:"What is the correct IUPAC name for NO2",option:{a:"Dioxonitrate(III) ion",b:"Dioxonitrate(IV) ION",c:"trioxonitrate(iii) ion",d:"trioxonitrate(iv) ion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:101,question:` CO(g) + H2O(g) ⇌  CO2(g)  +  H2(g)
From the reaction above, calculate the standard heat change if the standard enthalpies of formation of CO2 (g), H2O (g) and CO (g) in kJ mol-1 are -394, -242 and -110 respectively.
`,option:{a:"-262 kJ  mol-1",b:"-42kJ mol-1",c:"+42 kJ mol-1",d:"+262 kJ mol-1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is an example of a mixture",option:{a:"Blood",b:"Sand",c:"Washing soda",d:"Common salt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:145,question:"In the electrolysis of brine, the anode is",option:{a:"Platinum",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:267,question:"The stability of the noble gases is due to the fact that they",option:{a:"Have duplet or octet electron configurations",b:"Belong to group zero of the periodic table",c:"Are volatile in nature",d:"Have no electron in their outermost shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:257,question:"Group IA metals are not found free in nature because they",option:{a:"Have high melting and boiling points",b:"Conduct heat and electricity",c:"Are very reactive and unstable",d:"Are malleable and ductile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:226,question:"What is the mola. Mass of a substance, if 0.4 mole of the substance has a mass of 25.0g",option:{a:"6.3g",b:"40.0g",c:"62.5g",d:"2.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:258,question:"The characteristic colour of the flame shown when a copper salt moistened with concentrated hydrochloric acid on platinum is put on a bunzen burner is",option:{a:"Green",b:"Lilac",c:"Yellow",d:"Brick-red"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:297,question:"Benzene reacts with hydrogen in the presence of nickel catalyst at 1800C to give",option:{a:"Toluene",b:"Cyclopentane",c:"Cyclohexane",d:"Xylene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:231,question:"A particle that contain s 11protons, 12 neutrons and 10 electrons is probably a",option:{a:"Metallic ion",b:"Non-metallic ion",c:"Neutral metal",d:"Neutral non-metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:61,question:"If 0.75 mole of cyclopropane and 0.66 mole of oxygen are mixed in a vessel with a total pressure of 0.7 atmosphere. What is the partial pressure of oxygen in the mixture",option:{a:"0.55 atmosphere",b:"0.44 atmosphere",c:"0.33 atmosphere",d:"0.22 atmosphere"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:234,question:"A degree in atomic size and an increase in knuckler charge across a period lead to",option:{a:"A decrease in covalency in bond formation",b:"An increase in chemical reactivity",c:"An increase in the tendency to loss electrons",d:"A decrease in electro positivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:208,question:"A concentrated solution containing H+, Cu2+, OH- and Cl- was electrolyzed using platinum electrodes. The ion that will be discharged at the cathode is",option:{a:"OH-",b:"Cl-",c:"Cu2+",d:"H+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:166,question:"The reaction above is",option:{a:"Carboxylation",b:"Decarboxylation",c:"Acidification",d:"Esterification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:282,question:"Iron can be protected from corrosion by coating the surface with",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Gold"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:239,question:"One mole of a hydrocarbon contains 36g of carbon and its vapour density is 20. The structure of the hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"CH3CH2CH3",b:"CH3CH = CH2",c:"CH3CH2C = CH",d:"CH3C = CH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:90,question:"A liquid that will dissolve fast is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric acid",b:"Calcium hydroxide",c:"Kerosene",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:207,question:"In which of the following reactions can the oxidation number of nitrogen be said to have increased",option:{a:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) →   Fe(NO)SO4(S)",b:"2NO(g)  +  O2(g) → 2NO2(g)",c:"NO(g)  +  CI2(g)  → NOCI2(l)",d:"NO(g)  +  Br2(l)   → NOBr2(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:74,question:"The boiling of fat and aqueous caustic soda is referred as",option:{a:"Saponification",b:"Esterification",c:"Acidification",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:77,question:"What is the percentage by mass of oxygen in Al2(SO4)3.2H2O",option:{a:"14.29%",b:"25.39%",c:"50.79%",d:"59.25%"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:70,question:"The most important use of hydrogen is in the",option:{a:"Hydrogenation of oils",b:"Manufacture of methyl alcohol",c:"Manufacture of ammonia",d:"Manufacture of ethyl alcohol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:217,question:"Na2CO3(aq)  +  2HCI(aq)  → 2NaCI(aq)  +  H2O(l)  +  CO2(g)    How many moles of sodium trioxocarbonate (IV) are there in a 25cm3 solution which required 10cm3 of 0.05 mol dm-3 hydrochloric acid solution to neutralize it?",option:{a:"0.100mloe",b:"0.001mole",c:"1.000mole",d:"0.010mole"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:277,question:"Calculate the volume of 0.5 mol dm-3 H2SO4 that is neutralized by 25cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH",option:{a:"2.5cm3",b:"0.4cm3",c:"0.1cm3",d:"5.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:284,question:"In which of the following is the entropy change positive",option:{a:"Reaction between an acid and a base",b:"Addition of concentrated acid to water",c:"Dissolution of sodium metal in water",d:"Thermal dissociation of ammonium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:49,question:"The chromatographic separation of ink is based on the ability of the components to",option:{a:"React with each other",b:"React with the solvent",c:"Dissolve in each other in the column",d:"Move at different speeds in the column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:266,question:"How many unpaired electron(s) are there in the nitrogen  sub - levels",option:{a:"2",b:"1",c:"0",d:"3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:300,question:"The correct order of increasing boiling points of the following  compounds C3H7OH, C7H16 and C4H10 is",option:{a:"C4H10  →  C7H16 → C3H7OH",b:"C7H16 → C3H7OH → C4H16",c:"C4H10  → C3H7OH  → C4H10",d:"C3H7OH →  C4H10  → C7H16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:215,question:"Which of the following ions requires the largest quantity of electricity for discharge at an electrode",option:{a:"2.5 moles of Cu2+",b:"4.0 moles of CI-",c:"2.0 moles of Al3+",d:"3.0 moles of Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:118,question:"Ethanol reacts with excess acidified K2Cr2O7 to produce",option:{a:"Ethanoic acid",b:"Ethanol",c:"Ethyl ethanoate",d:"Ethanoic acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:38,question:"A characteristic reaction of the compounds with the general formula CnH2n is",option:{a:"Esterification",b:"Polymerization",c:"Decarboxylation",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:212,question:"What will happen if an aluminum spoon is used to stir a solution of iron (II) trioxonitrate(V)",option:{a:"The spoon will be reduced while the iron(II) ions will be oxidized",b:"The spoon will be oxidized while the iron (II) ions will be reduced to the metal",c:"The spoon will be reduced",d:"The spoon will increase in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:206,question:"The gas that is the most dangerous pollutant to humans is",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide",b:"Nitrogen (II)oxide",c:"Hydrogen sulphide",d:"Sulphur(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:99,question:"When at equilibrium, which of the reactions below will shift to the right if the pressure is increased and the temperature is kept constant",option:{a:" 2SO3(g)  ⇌  2SO2(g)  +  O2(g)",b:" 2CO2(g)  ⇌ 2CO(g)  +  O2(g)",c:" 2H2(g)  +  O2(g) ⇌  2H2O(g)",d:" 2NO(g)   ⇌ N2(g)  +  O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:182,question:"The pressure of 100cm3 of oxygen at 350C is 750mmHg. What will be the volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to 100mmHg  without changing the temperature",option:{a:"850cm3",b:"750cm3",c:"650cm3",d:"580cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:170,question:"The property used in the industrial preparation of nitrogen and oxygen from air is",option:{a:"Rate of diffusion",b:"Solubility",c:"Density",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:136,question:"Pollution of underground water by metal ions is very likely in a soil that has high",option:{a:"Acidity",b:"Alkalinity",c:"Chloride content",d:"Nitrate content"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:110,question:"Chlorine gas turns a damp starch-iodide paper",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Colourless",c:"Red",d:"Dark blue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:58,question:"The solubility of a salt of molar mass 101g at 200C is 0.34mol dm-3. If 3.40g of the salt is dissolved completely in 250cm3 of water in a beaker, the resulting solution is",option:{a:"Unsaturated",b:"A suspension",c:"Saturated",d:"Supersaturated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:84,question:"A gas exerts pressure on its container because",option:{a:"Some of its molecules are moving faster than others",b:"Of the collision of the molecules with each other",c:"Of the mass of the molecules of gas",d:"The molecules of a gas collide with the walls of the container"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:59,question:"25cm3 of a 0.2mol dm-3 solution of Na2CO3 requires 20cm3 of  solution of HCl for neutralization. The concentration of the solution is",option:{a:"0.6 mol dm-3",b:"0.5 mol dm-3",c:"0.4 mol dm-3",d:"0.2 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:171,question:"A dense white fume is formed when ammonia gas reacts with",option:{a:"H2(g)",b:"O2(g)",c:"HCI(g)",d:"Cl2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:69,question:"Hydrogen is readily released when dilute hydrochloric acid reacts with",option:{a:"Au",b:"Cu",c:"Na",d:"Ag"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:259,question:"The ion that will give a white precipitate with aqueous NaOH and soluble in excess of the base is",option:{a:"Zn2+",b:"Mg2+",c:"Ca2+",d:"Cu2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:225,question:"The solution that will conduct the highest amount of electricity is",option:{a:"2.0 moldm-3 of ethanoic acid",b:"0.5 mol dm-3 of ethanoic acid",c:"2.0 mol dm-3 of hydrochloric acid",d:"0.5 moldm-3 of hydrochloric acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:235,question:"The idea of planetary electrons was that of",option:{a:"Bohr",b:"Thompson",c:"Rutherford",d:"Dalton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:132,question:"The property of chlorine which causes hydrogen chloride to be more ionic than the chlorine molecule is its",option:{a:"Electrovalency",b:"Electron affinity",c:"Electropositivity",d:"Electronegativity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:33,question:"During the vulcanization of rubber, sulphur is added to",option:{a:"Break down rubber polymer",b:"Lengthen the chain of rubber",c:"Bind rubber molecules together",d:"Act as a catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:155,question:"Carbon is tetravalent because",option:{a:"The electrons in both the 2s and 2p orbitals are equivalent",b:"The electrons in all the orbitals of carbon are equivalent",c:"The 2s and 2p atomic orbitals hybridize",d:"All the atomic orbitals of carbon hybridize"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:113,question:"Carbohydrates are compounds containing carbon, hydrogen and oxygen in the ratio",option:{a:"3:01:01",b:"2:01:01",c:"1:02:01",d:"1:01:01"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:304,question:"The compound that is used as an anaesthetic is",option:{a:"CHCI3",b:"CH2C2",c:"CH3CI",d:"CCI4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:169,question:"The gas that can be dried using concentrated Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid is",option:{a:"Ammonia",b:"Hydrogen bromide",c:"Sulphur (IV) oxide",d:"Hydrogen sulphide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:127,question:"According to Charles  law, the volume of a gas becomes zero at",option:{a:"00C",b:"-1000C",c:"-2730C",d:"-3730C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:3,question:"A particle that contains 9 protons, 10 neutrons and 10electrons is a",option:{a:"Neghative ion",b:"Positive ion",c:"Neutral atom of a non metal",d:"Neutral atom of a metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:30,question:"Fermentation is the",option:{a:"Breaking down of carbohydrate to glucose",b:"Conversion of sugar to alcohol in the presence of yeast",c:"Breaking down of sugar to carbohydrate",d:"Conversion of alcohol to sugar in the presence of yeast"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:285,question:"If a reaction is exothermic and thee is a great disorder, it means that",option:{a:"The reaction is in a state of equilibrium",b:"There will be a large increase in free energy",c:"There will be a large decrease in free energy",d:"The reaction is static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:205,question:"When water boilers are used for a long period of time, the solid substances left behind as scale are",option:{a:"Magnesium trioxosilicate (IV) and calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Magnesium trioxosilicate(IV) and rust",c:"Clay and magnesium trioxosilicate (IV)",d:"clay and rust"},section:"",image:"",answer:"",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:241,question:"Nigerian crude oil is described as light crude because of its",option:{a:"Low aliphatic hydrocarbon content",b:"Low sulphur content",c:"High natural gas content",d:"High octane number"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:117,question:"The type of reaction that is peculiar to benzene is",option:{a:"Addition",b:"Hydrolysis",c:"Polymerization",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:181,question:"The most abundant element on the earth’s crust is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Fluorine",c:"hydrogen",d:"nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:79,question:"3Cu  +  pHNO3  → 3Cu(NO3)2  +  4H2O  + xNO   In the equation above, the values of p and x respectively are",option:{a:"1 and 3",b:"2 and 3",c:"6 and 2",d:"8 and 2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:154,question:" sulphur (IV) oxide bleaches by",option:{a:"Reduction",b:"Oxidation",c:"Hydration",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,e as message,a as status,o as subject,i as total};
